The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit
从数百个麻省理工学院的课程中访问
MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw.mit.edu
麻省理工学院的开放式课件网站ocw.mit.edu
PROFESSOR: All right, let's get started.
教授：好的，让我们开始吧。
We return today to graph search.
我们今天返回图搜索。
Last time we saw breadth-first search, today we're
上次我们看到广度优先搜索时，今天我们是
going to do depth-first search.
将进行深度优先搜索。
It's a simple algorithm, but you can do lots of cool things
这是一个简单的算法，但是您可以做很多很酷的事情
with it.
用它。
And that's what I'll spend most of today
这就是我今天大部分时间的时间
on, in particular, telling whether your graph has a cycle,
特别是告诉您的图表是否具有循环，
and something called topological sort.
以及所谓的拓扑排序
As usual, basically in all graph algorithms
像往常一样，基本上在所有图算法中
in this class, the input, the way the graph is specified
在此类中，输入是指定图形的方式
is as an adjacency list, or I guess adjacency list plural.
是作为邻接表，或者我猜邻接表是复数形式。
So you have a bunch of lists, each one says for each vertex,
因此，您有一堆清单，每个清单针对每个顶点说，
what are the vertices I'm connected to?
我连接到的顶点是什么？
What are the vertices I can get to in one step via an edge?
我可以通过一条边一步到达哪些顶点？
So that's our input and our goal,
这就是我们的投入和目标，
in general, with graph search is to explore the graph.
通常，使用图搜索是要探索图。
In particular, the kind of exploration
特别是那种探索
we're going to be doing today is to visit all the vertices,
我们今天要做的是访问所有顶点
in some order, and visit each vertex only once.
以某种顺序访问每个顶点一次。
So the way we did breadth-first search,
所以我们进行广度优先搜索的方式
breadth-first search was really good.
广度优先搜索的确很好。
It explored things layer by layer,
它逐层探索事物，
and that was nice because it gave us shortest paths,
很好，因为它给了我们最短的路径，
it gave us the fastest way to get to everywhere,
它为我们提供了前往各个地方的最快方式，
from a particular source, vertex s.
来自特定来源vertex。
But if you can't get from s to your vertex,
但是，如果您无法从s到达顶点，
than the shortest way to get there is infinity,
比到达那里的最短方法是无限
there's no way to get there.
没有办法到达那里。
And BFS is good for detecting that, it can tell you
BFS可以很好地检测到它，它可以告诉您
which vertices are unreachable from s.
从s不能到达哪个顶点。
DFS can do that as well, but it's often
DFS也可以做到这一点，但是通常
used to explore the whole graph, not just
用于探索整个图，而不仅仅是
the part reachable from s, and so
可从s到达的部分，依此类推
we're going to see how to do that today.
我们今天要看看如何做到这一点。
This trick could be used for be BFS or for DFS,
这个技巧可以用于BFS或DFS，
but we're going to do it here for DFS, because that's
但是我们将在这里为DFS进行操作，因为那是
more common, let's say.
比方说，更常见。
So DFS.
所以DFS。
So depth-first search is kind of like how you solve a maze.
因此，深度优先搜索就像解决迷宫一样。
Like, the other weekend I was at the big corn
就像，另一个周末我在大玉米
maze in central Massachusetts, and it's
在马萨诸塞州中部的迷宫，
easy to get lost in there, in particular,
特别容易在那儿迷路
because I didn't bring any bread crumbs.
因为我没有带面包屑
The proper way to solve a maze, if you're in there
解决迷宫的正确方法（如果您在其中）
and all you can do is see which way to go next and then walk
而您所能做的就是看看下一步该走什么路然后走
a little bit to the next junction,
到下一个路口
and then you have to keep making decisions.
然后你必须继续做决定。
Unless you have a really good memory, which I do not,
除非你的记忆力真的很好，否则我不会
teaching staff can attest to that, then an easy way to do it
教学人员可以证明这一点，然后便是一种简单的方法
is to leave bread crumbs behind, say,
就是把面包屑留在后面
this is the last way I went from this node,
这是我从该节点出发的最后一条路，
so that when I reach a deadend, I
这样当我到达死胡同时
have to turn around and backtrack.
必须转身回去。
I reach a breadcrumb that say, oh, last time you
我碰到面包屑说，哦，上一次你
went this way, next time you should go this way,
这样，下次您应该这样，
and in particular, keep track at each node, which of the edges
尤其要跟踪每个节点上的哪些边
have I visited, which ones are still left to visit.
我有去过吗，哪些还留着去。
And this can be done very easily on a computer using recursion.
使用递归可以很容易地在计算机上完成此操作。
So high-level description is we're
因此，高层次的描述是
going to just recursively explore the graph,
只是递归地浏览图，
backtracking as necessary, kind of like how you solve a maze.
必要时回溯，就像解决迷宫一样。
In fact, when I was seven years old,
实际上，我七岁的时候
one of the first computer programs I wrote
我写的第一批计算机程序之一
was for solving a maze.
是为了解决迷宫。
I didn't know it was depth-first search at the time,
我当时不知道这是深度优先搜索，
but now I know.
但现在我知道了。
It was so much harder doing algorithms
做算法要困难得多
when I didn't know what they were.
当我不知道他们是什么时候。
Anyway, I'm going to write some code for depth-first search,
无论如何，我将为深度优先搜索编写一些代码，
it is super simple code, the simplest graph algorithm.
它是超级简单的代码，最简单的图形算法。
It's four lines.
这是四行。
That's it.
而已。
I'm going to write a little bit of code after this,
之后，我要写一些代码，
but this is basic depth-first search.
但这是基本的深度优先搜索。
This will visit all the vertices reachable
这将访问所有可到达的顶点
from a given source, vertex s.
来自给定来源的顶点s。
So we're given the adjacency list.
因此，我们得到了邻接表。
I don't know why I put v here, you could erase it,
我不知道为什么我把v放在这里，你可以删除它，
it's not necessary.
这不是必需的。
And all we do is, we have our vertex b, sorry,
我们要做的就是，拥有顶点b，对不起，
we have our vertex s.
我们有顶点。
We look at all of the outgoing edges from s.
我们查看s的所有传出边。
For each one, we'll call it v, we check,
对于每个，我们将其称为v，我们检查一下，
have I visited this vertex already?
我已经访问过这个顶点了吗？
A place where we need to be careful
我们需要注意的地方
is to not repeat vertices.
是不重复顶点。
We need to do this in BFS as well.
我们也需要在BFS中执行此操作。
So, the way we're going to do that
所以，我们要做的方式
is by setting the parent of a node,
通过设置节点的父节点，
we'll see what that actually means later.
我们稍后会看到实际含义。
But for now, it's just, are you in the parent structure or not?
但是现在，仅仅是，您是否在父结构中？
This is initially, we've seen s, so we give it
最初是，我们已经看过s，所以我们给它
a parent of nothing, but it exists in this dictionary.
没有任何东西的父母，但它存在于这本词典中。
If the vertex b that we're looking at
如果我们正在寻找的顶点b
is not in our dictionary, we haven't seen it yet,
不在我们的字典中，我们还没有看过，
we mark it as seen by setting its parent to s,
我们通过将其父级设置为s将其标记为可见，
and then we recursively visit it.
然后我们递归地访问它。
That's it.
而已。
Super simple, just recurse.
超级简单，只需递归即可。
Sort of the magical part is the preventing yourself
不可思议的部分是预防自己
from repeating.
从重复。
As you explore the graph, if you reach something
当您浏览图表时，如果达到目标
you've already seen before you just skip it again.
您已经看到了，然后再次跳过。
So you only visit every vertex once, at most once.
因此，您仅一次访问每个顶点，最多只能访问一次。
This will not visit the entire graph,
这不会访问整个图，
it will only visit the vertices reachable from s.
它只会访问从s可达的顶点。
The next part of the code I'd like to give you
我想给你的代码的下一部分
is for visiting all the vertices, and in the textbook
用于访问所有顶点，并且在教科书中
this is called the DFS, whereas this is just
这称为DFS，而这仅仅是
called DFS visit, that's sort of the recursive part,
称为DFS访问，这是递归部分，
and this is sort of a top level algorithm.
这是一种顶级算法。
Here we are going to use the set of vertices, b,
在这里，我们将使用一组顶点b
and here we're just going to iterate over the s's.
在这里，我们只是要遍历s。
So it looks almost the same, but what we're iterating over
所以看起来几乎一样，但是我们要迭代的是
is different.
是不同的。
Here we're iterating over the outgoing edges from s,
在这里，我们迭代s的输出边缘，
here were iterating over the choices of s.
这里是对s的选择进行迭代。
So the idea here is we don't really
所以这里的想法是我们不是真的
know where to start our search.
知道从哪里开始搜索。
If it's a disconnected graph or not a strongly connected graph,
如果它是断开连接的图或不是高度连接的图，
we might have to start our search multiple times.
我们可能不得不多次开始搜索。
This DFS algorithm is finding all the possible places
此DFS算法正在查找所有可能的位置
you might start the search and trying them all.
您可以开始搜索并尝试全部操作。
So it's like, OK, let's try the first vertex.
就像，好吧，让我们尝试第一个顶点。
If that hasn't been visited, which initially nothing's been
如果没有被访问过，那么最初什么都没有
visited, then visit it, recursively, everything
访问，然后递归访问所有内容
reachable from s.
可从s到达。
Then you go on to the second vertex.
然后进入第二个顶点。
Now, you may have already visited it, then you skip it.
现在，您可能已经访问过它，然后跳过它。
Third vertex, maybe you visited it already.
第三顶点，也许您已经访问过它。
Third, fourth vertex, keep going,
第三，第四顶点，继续前进，
until you find some vertex you haven't visited at all.
直到找到某个顶点，您才完全没有访问过。
And then you recursively visit everything reachable from it,
然后您递归地访问所有可以访问的内容，
and you repeat.
然后重复
This will find all the different clusters,
这将找到所有不同的集群，
all the different strongly connected components
所有不同的强连接组件
of your graph.
您的图表。
Most of the work is being done by this recursion,
大多数工作是通过此递归完成的，
but then there's this top level, just
但是那里有这个顶级
to make sure that all the vertices get visited.
确保访问所有顶点。
Let's do a little example, so this is super clear,
让我们做一个例子，这很清楚，
and then it will also let me do something
然后它也可以让我做点什么
called edge classification.
称为边缘分类。
Once we see every edge in the graph
一旦我们看到了图中的每个边缘
gets visited by DFS in one way or another,
被DFS以一种或另一种方式访问​​，
and it's really helpful to think about the different ways
考虑一下不同的方式真的很有帮助
they can be visited.
他们可以被访问。
So here's a graph.
这是一张图。
I think its a similar to one from last class.
我认为它与上一堂课相似。
It's not strongly connected, I don't think,
它没有紧密的联系，我不认为，
so you can't get from these vertices to c.
因此您无法从这些顶点到达c。
You can get from c to everywhere,
您可以从c到任何地方，
it looks like, but not strongly connected.
看起来像，但联系不紧密。
And we're going to run DFS, and I think, basically
我们将运行DFS，我认为基本上
in alphabetical order is how we're imagining--
我们想像中的字母顺序
these vertices have to be ordered somehow,
这些顶点必须以某种方式排序，
we don't really care how, but for sake of example I care.
我们并不真正在乎，但是为了举例，我在乎。
So we're going to start with a, that's
所以我们将从a开始，那就是
the first vertex in here.
这里的第一个顶点。
We're going to recursively visit everything reachable from a,
我们将递归地访问从
so we enter here with s equals a.
所以我们在这里输入s等于a。
So I'll mark this s1, to be the first value of s at this level.
因此，我将此s1标记为s在此级别的第一个值。
So we consider-- I'm going to check the order here--
所以我们考虑-我要在这里检查订单-
first edge we look at, there's two outgoing edges,
我们看的第一个边缘，有两个向外的边缘，
let's say we look at this one first.
假设我们先来看这个。
We look at b, b has not been visited yet,
我们看一下b，b还没有被访问过，
has no parent pointer.
没有父指针。
This one has a parent pointer of 0.
该对象的父指针为0。
B we're going to give a parent pointer of a, that's here.
B，我们将给它一个父指针。
Then we recursively visit everything for b.
然后，我们递归地访问b的所有内容。
So we look at all the outgoing edges from b, there's only one.
因此，我们查看b的所有出局边，只有一个。
So we visit this edge.
因此，我们访问了此边缘。
for b to e. e has not been visited,
从b到e。尚未访问过e
so we set as parent pointer to b, an now we recursively visit
因此我们将其设置为b的父指针，然后递归访问
e.
e。
e has only one outgoing edge, so we look at it, over here to d.
e只有一个向外的边缘，因此我们在d处进行观察。
d has not been visited, so we set a parent pointer to e,
d尚未被访问，因此我们将父指针设置为e，
and we look at all the outgoing edges from d.
我们看一下d的所有出射边。
d has one outgoing edge, which is
d有一个传出边，即
to b. b has already been visited,
到b。 b已经被访问过，
so we skip that one, nothing to do.
因此，我们跳过了那个，无所事事。
That's the else case of this if, so we
如果这是其他情况，那么我们
do nothing in the else case, we just go to the next edge.
在其他情况下什么也不做，我们只是转到下一个边缘。
But there's no next edge for d, so we're done.
但是d没有下一个边缘，所以我们完成了。
So this algorithm returns to the next level up.
因此，该算法返回到更高的层次。
Next level up was e, we were iterating
下一个升级是e，我们正在迭代
over the outgoing edges from e.
在e的输出边缘上。
But there was only one, so we're done, so e finishes.
但是只有一个，所以我们完成了，所以结束了。
Then we backtrack to b, which is always going back
然后我们回溯到b，它总是回溯
along the parent pointer, but it's also just
沿着父指针，但这也只是
in the recursion.
在递归中。
We know where to go back to.
我们知道该去哪里。
We were going over the outgoing edges from b, there's only one,
我们正从b移出边缘，只有一个，
we're done.
我们完成了。
So we go back to a.
所以我们回到a。
We only looked at one outgoing edge from a.
我们仅查看了a的一个传出边。
There's another outgoing edge, which is this one,
还有另一个向外的优势，就是这个
but we've already visited d, so we skip over that one,
但是我们已经访问了d，所以我们跳过了那个，
too, so we're done recursively visiting
也是如此，所以我们完成了递归访问
everything reachable from a.
一切都可以从一个。
Now we go back to this loop, the outer loop.
现在我们回到这个循环，外循环。
So we did a, next we look at b, we say, oh b has been visited,
所以我们做了a，接下来我们看b，说哦，b已经被访问过，
we don't need to do anything from there.
我们不需要在那里做任何事情。
Then we go to c, c hasn't been visited
然后我们去c，c还没去过
so we're going to loop from c, and so this
所以我们要从c循环，所以这
is our second choice of s in this recursion,
是此递归中s的第二选择，
or in this outer loop.
或在此外部循环中。
And so we look at the outgoing edges from s2,
因此，我们看一下s2的输出边，
let me match the order in the notes.
让我匹配笔记中的顺序。
Let's say first we go to f.
假设首先我们转到f。
f has not been visited, so we set its parent pointer to c.
f尚未被访问，因此我们将其父指针设置为c。
Then we look at all the outgoing edges from f.
然后，我们查看f的所有传出边。
There's one outgoing edge from f, it goes to f.
f有一个传出边缘，到f。
I guess I shouldn't really bold this, sorry.
对不起，我想我不应该对此加粗。
I'll say what the bold edges mean in a moment.
我先说一下粗体字的含义。
This is just a regular edge.
这只是一个常规的优势。
We follow the edge from f to f.
我们沿着边缘从f到f。
We see, oh, f has already been visited,
我们看到哦，f已经被访问过了，
it already has a parent pointer, so there's
它已经有一个父指针，所以有
no point going down there.
没有意义下去。
We're done with f, that's the only outgoing edge.
f做完了，这是唯一的输出边缘。
We go back to c, there's one other outgoing edge,
回到c，还有另一个输出边，
but it leads to a vertex we've already visited, namely e,
但这会导致我们已经访问过一个顶点，即e，
and so we're done with visiting everything reachable from c.
因此，我们完成了访问c可以访问的所有操作的步骤。
We didn't visit everything reachable
我们没有访问所有可以到达的地方
from c, because some of it was already visited from a.
来自c，因为其中一些已经从a访问过。
Then we go back to the outer loop, say, OK, what about d?
然后我们回到外循环，说，好，那d呢？
D has been visited, what about e?
D已经被访问过，e呢？
E's been visited, what about f?
E被访问过，f呢？
F's been visited.
F已被访问。
So we're visiting these vertices again,
所以我们再次访问这些顶点，
but should only be twice in total, and in the end
但总共应该只有两次，最后
we visit all the vertices, and, in a certain sense,
我们访问所有顶点，在某种意义上，
all the edges as well.
所有的边缘。
Let's talk about running time.
让我们谈谈运行时间。
What do you think the running time of this algorithm is?
您认为该算法的运行时间是多少？
Anyone?
任何人？
Time to wake up.
起床时间到了。
AUDIENCE: Upper bound?
听众：上限？
PROFESSOR: Upper bound, sure.
教授：当然可以。
AUDIENCE: V?
听众：V？
PROFESSOR: V?
教授：V？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: V is a little bit optimistic, plus e, good,
教授：V有点乐观，再加上e，很好，
collaborative effort.
共同努力。
It's linear time, just like BFS.
就像BFS一样，它是线性时间。
This is what we call linear time,
这就是我们所说的线性时间
because this is the size of the input.
因为这是输入的大小。
It's theta V plus E for the whole thing.
整个过程是theta V +E。
The size of the input was v plus e.
输入的大小为v加上e。
We needed v slots in an array, plus we
我们需要阵列中的v插槽，再加上
needed e items in these linked lists, one for each edge.
这些链接列表中需要e个项目，每个边缘一个。
We have to traverse that whole structure.
我们必须遍历整个结构。
The reason it's order v plus e is-- first, as you were saying,
之所以加上v和e，是因为-首先，正如您所说的，
you're visiting every vertex once in this outer loop,
您在此外循环中访问了每个顶点一次，
so not worrying about the recursion in DFS alone,
因此不必担心仅在DFS中进行递归，
so that's order b.
这就是命令b。
Then have to worry about this recursion,
然后要担心这种递归
but we know that whenever we call DFS visit on a vertex,
但是我们知道，每当我们调用顶点上的DFS访问时，
that it did not have a parent before.
它以前没有父母。
Right before we called DFS visit,
在我们叫DFS访问之前，
we set its parent for the first time.
我们是第一次设置它的父对象。
Right before we called DFS visit on v here,
就在我们在这里调用DFS访问v之前，
we set as parent for the first time,
我们第一次设置为父级
because it wasn't set before.
因为它不是以前设置的。
So DFS visit, and I'm going to just write of v,
DFS访问，我将只写v
meaning the last argument here.
意思是这里的最后一个论点。
It's called once, at most once, per vertex b.
每个顶点b最多调用一次。
But it does not take constant time.
但这并不需要固定的时间。
This takes constant time per vertex, plus a recursive call.
这需要每个顶点恒定的时间，以及递归调用。
This thing, this takes constant time, but there's a for loop
这个东西，这需要恒定的时间，但是有一个for循环
here.
这里。
We have to pay for however many outgoing edges
但是，我们必须为许多外向的边缘付费
there are from b, that's the part you're missing.
来自b，那是您缺少的部分。
And we pay length of adjacency of v for that vertex.
我们为该顶点支付v的邻接长度。
So the total in addition to this v
所以除了这个v
is going to be the order, sum overall vertices, v in capital
将是顺序，求总顶点之和，v等于大写
V, of length of the adjacency, list for v,
V，邻接长度，v的列表，
which is E. This is the handshaking
这是E。这是握手
lemma from last time.
上次的引理。
It's twice e for undirected graphs,
对于无向图，它是e的两倍，
it's e for directed graphs.
它是有向图的e。
I've drawn directed graphs here, it's a little more interesting.
我在这里绘制了有向图，这有点有趣。
OK, so it's linear time, just like the BFS, so you could say,
好，这是线性时间，就像BFS，所以你可以说，
who cares, but DFS offers a lot of different properties
谁在乎，但DFS提供了许多不同的属性
than BFS.
比BFS。
They each have their niche.
他们每个人都有自己的利基。
BFS is great for shortest paths.
BFS非常适合最短的路径。
You want to know the fastest way to solve the Rubik's cube,
您想知道解决魔方的最快方法，
BFS will find it.
BFS将找到它。
You want to find the fastest way to solve the Rubik's cube,
您想找到最快的解决魔方的方法，
DFS will not find it.
DFS将找不到它。
It's not following shortest paths here.
这里没有遵循最短的路径。
Going from a to d, we use the path
从a到d，我们使用路径
of length 3, that's the bold edges.
长度为3的那是粗体边缘
We could have gone directly from a
我们本来可以直接从
to d, so it's a different kind of search,
到d，这是另一种搜索，
but sort of the inverse.
但有点相反。
But it's extremely useful, in particular, in the way
但这非常有用，特别是在
that it classifies edges.
它对边缘进行分类。
So let me talk about edge classification.
因此，让我谈谈边缘分类。
You can check every edge in this graph gets visited.
您可以检查该图中的每个边是否都已访问。
In a directed graph every edge gets visited once,
在有向图中，每个边都会被访问一次，
in an undirected graph, every edge
在无向图中，每个边
gets visited twice, once from each side.
被两次访问，一次从两侧。
And when you visit that edge, there's
当您访问该边缘时，
sort of different categories of what could happen to it.
可能发生的事情的不同类别。
Maybe the edge led to something unvisited, when you went there.
当您去那里的时候，也许边缘导致了一些未被发现的东西。
We call those tree edges.
我们称这些树的边缘。
That's what the parent pointers are specifying
那就是父指针所指定的
and all the bold edges here are called three edges.
此处所有粗体边缘称为三个边缘。
This is when we visit a new vertex via that edge.
这是当我们通过该边缘访问新顶点时。
So we look at the other side of the edge,
所以我们看边缘的另一侧，
we discover a new vertex.
我们发现了一个新的顶点。
Those are what we call tree edges,
这些就是我们所说的树边缘
it turns out they form a tree, a directed tree.
事实证明它们形成一棵树，一棵定向树。
That's a lemma you can prove.
您可以证明这是一个引理。
You can see it here.
在这里你可以看到它。
We just have a path, actually a forest would be more accurate.
我们只有一条路，实际上森林会更准确。
We have a path abed, and we have an edge cf,
我们有一条道路，还有一条边cf，
but, in general, it's a forest.
但总的来说，这是一片森林。
So for example, if there was another thing coming
例如，如果有另一件事
from e here, let's modify my graph, we would, at some point,
从这里开始，让我们修改我的图表，在某个时候，
visit that edge and say, oh, here's a new way to go,
拜访那个边缘，然后说，哦，这是一条新路要走，
and now that bold structure forms an actual tree.
现在，该粗体结构形成了实际的树。
These are called tree edges, you can call them forest edges
这些称为树边缘，您可以将它们称为森林边缘
if you feel like it.
如果您喜欢的话。
There are other edges in there, the nonbold edges,
那里还有其他边缘，非粗体边缘，
and the textbook distinguishes three types, three types?
教科书区分三种，三种？
Three types, so many types.
三种类型，那么多类型。
They are forward edges, backward edges, and cross edges.
它们是前边缘，后边缘和交叉边缘。
Some of these are more useful to distinguish than others,
其中有些比其他更有用，
but it doesn't hurt to have them all.
但是拥有它们全部并没有什么坏处。
So, for example, this edge I'm going to call a forward edge,
例如，我将这个边缘称为前向边缘，
just write f, that's unambiguous,
只需写f即可，
because it goes, in some sense, forward along the tree.
因为从某种意义上说，它沿着树前进。
It goes from the root of this tree to a descendant.
它从树的根到后代。
There is a path in the tree from a
树上有一条从
to d, so we call it a forward edge.
到d，所以我们称其为前缘。
By contrast, this edge I'm going to call a backward edge,
相比之下，我将这个边缘称为后向边缘，
because it goes from a node in the tree
因为它来自树中的一个节点
to an ancestor in the trees.
到树上的祖先。
If you think of parents, I can go from d to its parent
如果您想到父母，我可以从d转到父母
to its parent, and that's where the edge goes,
到父级，这就是优势所在，
so that's a backward edge-- double check I
所以这是一个落后的优势-仔细检查我
got these not reversed, yeah, that's right.
这些都没有逆转，是的，没错。
Forward edge because I could go from d to its parent
前缘，因为我可以从d转到其父级
to its parent to its parent and the edge
到其父级到其父级和边缘
went the other way, that's a forward edge.
相反，这是一个前沿。
So forward edge goes from a node to a descendant in the tree.
因此，前缘从节点到树中的后代。
Backward edge goes from a node to an ancestor in the tree.
向后边缘从树的节点到祖先。
And when I say, tree, I mean forest.
当我说树时，我是指森林。
And then all the other edges are cross edges.
然后其他所有边都是交叉边。
So I guess, here, this is a cross edge.
因此，我想这是一个交叉边缘。
In this case, it goes from one tree to another, doesn't
在这种情况下，它从一棵树到另一棵树
have to go between different trees.
必须在不同的树木之间穿行。
For example, let's say I'm visiting d, then
例如，假设我要访问d
I go back to e, I visit g, or there could be this edge.
我回到e，访问g，否则可能会出现这种情况。
If this edge existed, it would be a cross edge,
如果存在此边缘，则将是交叉边缘，
because g and d are not ancestor related,
因为g和d与祖先无关，
neither one is an ancestor of the other,
谁都不是对方的祖先，
they are siblings actually.
他们实际上是兄弟姐妹。
So there's, in general, there's going
因此，总的来说，
to be some subtree over here, some subtree over here,
成为这里的一些子树，这里的一些子树，
and this is a cross edge between two different subtrees.
这是两个不同子树之间的交叉边缘。
This cross edge is between two, sort of, non ancestor related,
这个交叉边缘介于两个与祖先无关的事物之间，
I think is the shortest way to write this, subtrees or nodes.
我认为这是写此子目录或节点的最短方法。
A little puzzle for you, well, I guess
我想你有点困惑
the first question is, how do you compute this structure?
第一个问题是，如何计算此结构？
How do you compute which edges are which?
您如何计算哪些边缘是哪个？
This is not hard, although I haven't written it in the code
这并不难，尽管我没有在代码中编写它
here.
这里。
You can check the textbook for one way to do it.
您可以检查教科书的一种方法。
The parent structure tells you which edges are tree edges.
父结构告诉您哪些边是树边。
So that part we have done.
至此我们已经完成了。
Every parent pointer corresponds to the reverse of a tree edge,
每个父指针对应于树边缘的反向，
so at the same time you could mark that edge a tree edge,
因此，您可以同时将该边缘标记为树边缘，
and you'd know which edges are tree edges
而且你会知道哪些边缘是树的边缘
and which edges are nontree edges.
以及哪些边缘是非树边缘。
If you want to know which are forward, which are backward,
如果您想知道哪些是前进的，哪些是后退的，
which are cross edges, the key thing you need to know
哪些是交叉边缘，您需要知道的关键
is, well, in particular, for backward edges, one way
尤其是对于后沿，一种方式
to compute them is to mark which nodes
计算它们就是标记哪些节点
you are currently exploring.
您正在探索。
So when we do a DFS visit on a node,
因此，当我们在节点上进行DFS访问时，
we could say at the beginning here,
我们可以在这里开始说
basically, we're starting to visit s, say, start s,
基本上，我们开始访问s，例如start，
and then at the end of this for loop, we write,
然后在此for循环的结尾，我们编写
we're finished with s.
我们以s结尾。
And you could mark that in the s structure.
您可以在s结构中进行标记。
You could say s dot in process is true up here,
您可以说这里的过程是真实的，
s dot in process equals false down here.
此处的s点等于false。
Keep track of which nodes are currently in the recursion
跟踪当前在递归中的节点
stack, just by marking them and unmarking them
堆栈，只需标记它们并取消标记
at the beginning and the end.
在开始和结束时。
Then we'll know, if we follow an edge and it's an edge
然后我们就会知道，如果我们跟随一条边缘，那就是一条边缘
to somebody who's already in the stack,
给已经在栈中的人，
then it's a backward edge, because that's-- everyone
那是一个落后的优势，因为那是-每个人
in the stack is an ancestor from our current node.
在堆栈中是我们当前节点的祖先。
Detecting forward edges, it's a little trickier.
检测前边缘，有点棘手。
Forward edges versus cross edges,
前边缘与交叉边缘，
any suggestions on an easy way to do that?
有什么简单的建议吗？
I don't think I know an easy way to do that.
我认为我不知道这样做的简单方法。
It can be done.
可以办到。
The way the textbook does it is a little bit more
教科书的处理方式
sophisticated, in that when they start visiting a vertex,
复杂的是，当他们开始访问顶点时，
they record the time that it got visited.
他们记录访问的时间。
What's time?
几点了？
You could think of it as the clock on your computer,
您可以将其视为计算机上的时钟，
another way to do it is, every time
另一种方法是每次
you do a step in this algorithm, you increment a counter.
您在此算法中执行了一个步骤，就增加了一个计数器。
So every time anything happens, you increment a counter,
所以每次发生任何事情时，您都增加一个计数器，
and then you store the value of that
然后您存储该值
counter here for s, that would be the start time for s,
在这里为s计数，这将是s的开始时间，
you store the finish time for s down here,
您将s的完成时间存储在这里，
and then this gives you, this tells you
然后这给你，这告诉你
when a node was visited, and you can
当访问节点时，您可以
use that to compute when an edge is a forward edge
用它来计算一条边何时是一条前边
and otherwise it's a cross edge.
否则就是交叉边缘。
It's not terribly exciting, though, so I'm not
不过，这并不令人兴奋，所以我没有
going to detail that.
详细说明。
You can look at the textbook if you're interested.
如果您有兴趣，可以看一下教科书。
But here's a fun puzzle.
但这是一个有趣的难题。
In an undirected graph, which of these edges can exist?
在无向图中，哪些边可以存在？
We can have a vote, do some democratic mathematics.
我们可以投票，做一些民主数学。
How many people think tree edges exist in undirected graphs?
有多少人认为树边存在于无向图中？
You, OK.
你还好吗。
Sarini does.
萨里尼做到了。
That's a good sign.
这是一个好兆头。
How many people think forward edges
有多少人认为前沿
exist in an undirected graph?
存在于无向图中吗？
A couple.
一对夫妇。
How many people think backward edges
有多少人认为后缘
exist in an undirected graph?
存在于无向图中吗？
Couple.
一对。
How many people think cross edges
有多少人认为交叉边缘
exist in undirected graph?
存在于无向图中？
More people, OK.
更多的人，好的。
I think voting worked.
我认为投票有效。
They all exist, no, that's not true.
它们都存在，不，那不是真的。
This one can exist and this one can exist.
这个可以存在，这个可以存在。
I actually wrote the wrong ones in my notes,
我实际上在笔记中写错了
so it's good to trick you, no, it's I made a mistake.
所以欺骗你很好，不，这是我犯了一个错误。
It's very easy to get these mixed up
将它们混合起来很容易
and you can think about why this is true,
您可以考虑为什么这是真的，
maybe I'll draw some pictures to clarify.
也许我会画一些图片来澄清。
This is something, you remember the-- there was BFS diagram,
您还记得-这是BFS图，
I talked a little bit about this last class.
我谈到了最后一堂课。
Tree edges better exist, those are the things
树木边缘更好地存在，这些就是东西
you use to visit new vertices.
您用来访问新顶点。
So that always happens, undirected or otherwise.
因此，这总是会发生，无论是无向的还是其他原因。
Forward edges, though, forward edge of
但是，前边缘
would be, OK, I visited this, then I visited this.
好的，我去过这里，然后我去过这里。
Those were tree edges.
那是树的边缘。
Then I backtrack and I follow an edge like this.
然后我回溯，然后跟随这样的优势。
This would be a forward edge.
这将是一个前沿。
And in a directed graph that can happen.
并且在有向图中可能发生。
In an undirected graph, it can also happen, right?
在无向图中也可能发生，对吧？
Oh, no, it can't, it can't.
哦，不，它不能，它不能。
OK.
好。
So confusing.
太混乱了
undirected graph, if you look like this,
无向图，如果您看起来像这样，
you start-- let's say this is s.
您开始-假设这是s。
You start here, and suppose we follow this edge.
您从这里开始，并假设我们遵循这一优势。
We get to here, then we follow this edge, we get to here.
我们到达这里，然后我们沿着这个边缘，我们到达这里。
Then we will follow this edge in the other direction,
然后，我们将沿着另一个方向走这个边缘，
and that's guaranteed to finish before we get back to s.
并保证在我们回到s之前完成。
So, in order to be a forward edge,
因此，为了成为前锋，
this one has to be visited after this one,
在此之后必须再次访问
from s, but in this scenario, if you follow this one first,
从s开始，但是在这种情况下，如果您先遵循这一点，
you'll eventually get to this vertex
您最终将到达这个顶点
and then you will come back, and then that will be classified
然后您会回来，然后将其分类
as a backward edge in an undirected graph.
作为无向图中的后沿。
So you can never have forward edges in an undirected graph.
因此，您永远都不能在无向图中拥有前缘。
But I have a backward edge here, that would suggest
但是我在这里有一个落后的优势，这表明
I can have backward edges here, and no cross edges.
我可以在这里有后边缘，而没有交叉边缘。
Well, democracy did not work, I was swayed by the popular vote.
好吧，民主是行不通的，我被民众投票所左右。
So I claim, apparently, cross edges do not exist.
因此，我声称显然不存在交叉边缘。
Let's try to draw this.
让我们尝试画这个。
So a cross edge typical scenario would be either here,
因此，跨边的典型场景要么在这里，
you follow this edge, you backtrack,
你遵循这一优势，回溯，
you follow another edge, and then
你跟随另一条边，然后
you discover there's was an edge back to some other subtree
你发现那里有一条回到其他子树的边缘
that you've already visited.
您已经访问过。
That can happen in an undirected graph.
这可能会在无向图中发生。
For the same reason, if I follow this one first,
出于同样的原因，如果我先遵循这一点，
and this edge exists undirected, then I will go down that way.
而且这条边缘是无向的，那么我将沿着这种方式下去。
So it will be actually tree edge, not a cross edge.
因此实际上是树边缘，而不是交叉边缘。
OK, phew.
好，
That means my notes were correct.
那表示我的笔记是正确的。
I was surprised, because they were
我很惊讶，因为他们
copied from the textbook, uncorrect my correction.
从教科书中抄袭，不正确我的更正。
Good.
好。
So what?
所以呢？
Why do I care about these edge classifications?
为什么我要关心这些边缘分类？
I claim they're super handy for two problems, cycle detection,
我声称它们非常方便解决两个问题，即循环检测，
which is pretty intuitive problem.
这是非常直观的问题。
Does my graph have any cycles?
我的图表有周期吗？
In the directed case, this is particularly interesting.
在定向情况下，这特别有趣。
I want to know, does a graph have any directed cycles?
我想知道，图是否有任何有向周期？
And another problem called topological sort,
还有另一个问题叫做拓扑排序
which we will get to.
我们会去的。
So let's start with cycle detection.
因此，让我们从循环检测开始。
This is actually a warmup for topological sort.
这实际上是对拓扑排序的热身。
So does my graph have any cycles?
那我的图有周期吗？
G has a cycle, I claim.
我声称G有一个循环。
This happens, if and only if, G has a back edge, or let's say,
当且仅当G具有后边缘，或者说，
a depth-first search of that graph has a back edge.
该图的深度优先搜索具有后沿。
So it doesn't matter where I start from
所以我从哪里开始都没关系
or how this algorithm-- I run this top level DFS algorithm,
或该算法的方式-我运行此顶级DFS算法，
explore the whole graph, because I
探索整个图，因为我
want to know in the whole graph is there a cycle?
想知道整个图中是否存在一个周期？
I claim, if there's a back edge, then there's a cycle.
我声称，如果有后缘，那就有一个循环。
So it all comes down to back edges.
因此，一切都落到了后沿。
This will work for both directed and undirected graphs.
这将适用于有向图和无向图。
Detecting cycles is pretty easy in undirected graphs.
在无向图中，检测周期非常容易。
It's a little more subtle with directed graphs,
有向图稍微有些微妙，
because you have to worry about the edge directions.
因为您必须担心边缘方向。
So let's prove this.
因此，让我们证明这一点。
We haven't done a serious proof in a while,
我们已经有一段时间没有做过认真的证明了，
so this is still a pretty easy one, let's think about it.
所以这仍然是很简单的，让我们考虑一下。
What do you think is the easier direction
您认为更容易的方向是什么
to prove here, left or right?
在这里证明是左还是右？
To more democracy.
为了更多的民主。
How many people think left is easy?
有多少人认为离开容易？
A couple.
一对夫妇。
How many people think right is easy?
有多少人认为正确很容易？
A whole bunch more.
一大堆。
I disagree with you.
恕我不能赞同。
I guess it depends what you consider easy.
我想这取决于您认为简单的事情。
Let me show you how easy left is.
让我向您展示左手有多容易。
Left is, I have a back edge, I want to claim there's a cycle.
左边是，我有一个后缘，我想声称这是一个循环。
What is the back edge look like?
后边缘是什么样的？
Well, it's an edge to an ancestor in the tree.
好吧，这是树上祖先的优势。
If this node is a descendant of this node
如果此节点是此节点的后代
and this node is an ancestor of this node, that's
这个节点是这个节点的祖先
saying there are tree edges, there's
说有树的边缘，有
a path, a tree path, that connects one to the other.
连接彼此的路径（树路径）。
So these are tree edges, because this
这些是树的边缘，因为
is supposed to be an ancestor, and this
应该是一个祖先
is supposed to be a descendant.
应该是后裔。
And that's the definition of a back edge.
这就是后边缘的定义。
Do you see a cycle?
你看到一个周期吗？
I see a cycle.
我看到一个周期。
This is a cycle, directed cycle.
这是一个循环，定向循环。
So if there's a back edge, by definition, it makes a cycle.
因此，根据定义，如果有后边缘，则将形成一个循环。
Now, it's harder to say if I have 10 back edges,
现在，很难说我是否有10个后缘，
how many cycles are there?
有多少个周期？
Could be many.
可能很多。
But if there's a back edge, there's
但是如果有后缘，
definitely at least one cycle.
肯定至少一个周期。
The other direction is also not too hard,
另一个方向也不太难
but I would hesitate to call it easy.
但我会毫不犹豫地说。
Any suggestions if, I know there is a cycle,
如果有任何建议，我知道有一个周期，
how do I prove that there's a back edge somewhere?
如何证明某处有后边缘？
Think about that, let me draw a cycle.
考虑一下，让我画一个周期。
There's a length k cycle.
有一个长度为k的循环。
Where do you think, which of these edges
您如何看待这些优势中的哪些优势
do you think is going to be a back edge?
您认为这将是后缘吗？
Let's hope it's one of these edges.
我们希望它是这些优势之一。
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: Vk to v zero.
听众：Vk到v零。
PROFESSOR: Vk to v zero.
教授：Vk至v零。
That's a good idea, maybe this is a back edge.
这是个好主意，也许这是后缘。
Of course, this is symmetric, why that edge?
当然，这是对称的，为什么具有这种优势？
I labeled it in a suggestive way,
我用暗示的方式标记了它
but I need to say something before I know actually which
但我需要先说些什么，然后才能真正知道
edge is going to be the back edge.
边缘将成为后边缘。
AUDIENCE: You have to say you start to v zero?
听众：你必须说你开始v零？
PROFESSOR: Start at v zero.
教授：从v零开始。
If I started a search of v zero, that
如果我开始搜索v零，那
looks good, because the search is
看起来不错，因为搜索是
kind of going to go in this direction.
会朝这个方向发展。
vk will maybe be the last thing to be visited,
vk可能是最后要访问的东西，
that's not actually true.
这不是真的。
Could be there's an edge directly from v zero to vk,
从v 0到vk可能存在一条边，
but intuitively vk will kind of later,
但是直觉上vk会在以后
and then when this edge gets visited,
然后当这个边缘被访问时，
this will be an ancestor and it will be a back edge.
这将是祖先，将是后缘。
Of course, we may not start a search here,
当然，我们可能不会在这里开始搜索，
so calling it the start of the search
所以称它为搜索的开始
is not quite right, a little different.
不太正确，有点不同。
AUDIENCE: First vertex that gets hit [INAUDIBLE].
听众：被击中的第一个顶点[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: First vertex that gets hit, good.
教授：碰到的第一个顶点，很好。
I'm going to start the numbering , v zero,
我将开始编号，v为零，
let's assume v 0 is the first vertex in the cycle,
假设v 0是循环中的第一个顶点，
visited by the depth-first search.
深度优先搜索访问过。
Together, if you want some pillows if you like them,
在一起，如果您想要一些枕头，如果您愿意，
especially convenient that they're in front.
他们在前面特别方便。
So right, if it's not v zero, say
好吧，如果它不是v零，说
v3 was the first one visited.
v3是第一个访问的网站。
We will just change the labeling,
我们只是更改标签，
so that's v zero, that's v1, that's v, and so on.
所以是v零，就是v1，就是v，依此类推。
So set this labeling, so that v0 first one,
因此设置该标签，以便v0成为第一个，
first vertex that gets visited.
被访问的第一个顶点。
Then, I claim that-- let me just write the claim first.
然后，我声明-让我先写声明。
This edge vkv0 will be a back edge.
该边缘vkv0将是后边缘。
We'll just say, is back edge.
我们只是说，是后缘。
And I would say this is not obvious, be a little careful.
我想说这并不明显，请多加注意。
We have to somehow exploit the depth-first nature of DFS,
我们必须以某种方式利用DFS的深度优先特性，
the fact that it goes deep-- it goes as deep as it can before
它变得更深的事实-它比以前更深入
backtracking.
回溯。
If you think about it, we're starting,
如果您考虑一下，我们就开始了，
at this point we are starting a search relative to this cycle.
在这一点上，我们正在开始相对于该周期的搜索。
No one has been visited, except v zero just
除v零外，没有人被访问过
got visited, has a parent pointer off somewhere else.
被访问时，将父指针移到其他地方。
What do we do next?
接下来我们要做什么？
Well, we visit all the outgoing edges from v zero,
好吧，我们访问从v零开始的所有传出边，
there might be many of them. it could
可能有很多。它可以
be edge from v zero to v1, it could an edge from v zero
是从v 0到v1的边，它可能是从v 0的边
to v3, it could be an edge from v zero to something else.
到v3，可能是从v 0到其他值的边缘。
We don't know which one's going to happen first.
我们不知道哪个会先发生。
But the one thing I can claim is that v1
但是我可以声称的一件事是v1
will be visited before we finish visiting v zero.
在完成访问v零之前将被访问。
From v zero, we might go somewhere else,
从v零开始，我们可能会去其他地方，
we might go somewhere else that might eventually
我们可能会去其他地方
lead to v1 by some other route, but in particular, we
通过其他途径引向v1，但特别是，我们
look at that edge from v zero to v1.
看一下从v 0到v1的那条边。
And so, at some point, we're searching,
因此，在某个时候，我们正在搜索，
we're visiting all the things reachable from v zero, that
我们正在访问从v零可到达的所有事物，
includes v1, and that will happen,
包括v1，这种情况将会发生，
we will touch v1 for the first time,
我们将第一次接触v1，
because it hasn't been touched yet.
因为还没有被触及
We will visit it before we finish visiting v zero.
我们将在完成访问v零之前访问它。
The same goes actually for all of v i's, because they're all
实际上，所有v i都是一样的，因为它们都是
reachable from v zero.
从v零可达。
You can prove this by induction.
您可以通过归纳证明这一点。
You'll have to visit v1 before you finish visiting v zero.
您必须先访问v1，然后才能完成对v零的访问。
You'll have to visit v2 before you finish visiting
您必须先访问v2，然后才能完成访问
v1, although you might actually visit v2 before v1.
v1，尽管您实际上可能在v1之前访问过v2。
You would definitely finish, you'll
你一定会完成，你会
finished v2 before you finish v1, and so on.
在完成v1之前先完成v2，依此类推。
So vi will be visited before you finish vi minus 1,
因此，在完成vi减去1之前，vi将被访问。
but in particular, what we care about is
但特别是我们关心的是
that vk is visited before we finish v zero.
在完成v零之前已访问了vk。
And it will be entirely visited.
它将完全被访问。
We will finish visiting vk before we
我们将在完成之前访问vk
finish visiting v zero.
完成访问v零。
We will start decay vk after we start to v zero,
我们将v设为零后开始衰减vk，
because v zero is first.
因为v零是第一个。
So the order is going to look like, start v zero,
因此，顺序看起来像是从v开始为零，
at some point we will start vk.
在某个时候，我们将启动vk。
Then we'll finish vk, then we'll finish v zero.
然后我们完成vk，然后我们完成v 0。
This is something the textbook likes to call,
这是教科书喜欢的东西，
and I like to call, balanced parentheses.
而且我喜欢用圆括号括起来。
You can think of it as, we start v zero, then we start vk,
您可以这样想，我们以v零开始，然后以vk开头，
then we finish vk, then we finish v zero.
然后完成vk，然后完成v 0。
And these match up and their balanced.
这些匹配并保持平衡。
Depth-first search always looks like that,
深度优先搜索总是这样，
because once you start a vertex, you
因为一旦开始顶点，
keep chugging until you visited all the things reachable
不断努力，直到您访问了所有可以到达的事物
from it.
从中。
Then you finish it.
然后，您完成它。
You won't finish v zero before you finish vk,
在完成vk之前，您不会完成v零，
because it's part of the recursion.
因为它是递归的一部分。
You can't return at a higher level
你不能再更高的水平了
before you return at the lower levels.
然后再返回较低的级别。
So we've just argued that the order
所以我们只是争辩说
is like this, because v zero was first,
就像这样，因为v零是第一个，
so vk starts after v zero, and also we're going to finish vk
所以vk在v零之后开始，而且我们还要完成vk
before we finish v zero, because it's reachable, and hasn't
在我们完成v零之前，因为它是可到达的，并且没有
been visited before.
曾经被访问过。
So, in here, we consider vkv zero.
因此，在这里，我们认为vkv为零。
When we consider that edge, it will be a back edge.
当我们考虑该边缘时，它将是后边缘。
Why?
为什么？
Because v zero is currently on the recursion stack,
由于v零​​当前位于递归堆栈上，
and so you will have marked v zero as currently in process.
因此您将当前标记为v零。
So when you look at that edge, you see it's a back edge,
因此，当您查看该边缘时，您会看到它是后边缘，
it's an edge to your ancestor.
这是您祖先的优势。
That's the proof.
那就是证明。
Any questions about that?
对此有任何疑问吗？
It's pretty easy once you set up the starting point, which
一旦设置了起点，这很容易
is look at the first time you visit the cycle,
是在您第一次访问周期时
than just think about how you walk around the cycle.
而不是仅仅考虑如何骑单车。
There's lots of ways you might walk around the cycle,
您可能有很多方法可以解决整个周期，
but it's guaranteed you'll visit vk at some point,
但可以保证您一定会访问vk，
then you'll look at the edge. v0 is still in the stack,
然后您将看看边缘。 v0仍在堆栈中，
so it's a back edge.
所以这是后缘。
And so this proves that having a cycle
所以这证明有一个循环
is equivalent to having a back edge.
等同于具有后边缘。
This gives you an easy linear time algorithm to tell,
这为您提供了一种简单的线性时间算法，可以告诉您，
does my graph have a cycle?
我的图有周期吗？
And if it does, it's actually easy to find one,
如果确实如此，实际上很容易找到一个，
because we find a back edge, just follow the tree edges,
因为我们找到了后边缘，所以只需跟随树的边缘，
and you get your cycle.
这样你就可以循环。
So if someone gives you a graph and say,
因此，如果有人给您一个图表并说，
hey, I think this is acyclic, you can very quickly say,
嘿，我认为这是非周期性的，您可以很快说
no, it's not, here's a cycle, or say,
不，不是，这是一个周期，或者说，
yeah, I agree, no back edges, I only have tree, forward,
是的，我同意，没有后缘，我只有一棵树，向前，
and cross edges.
和交叉边缘。
OK, that was application 1.
好的，那是应用程序1。
Application 2 is topological sort,
应用2是拓扑排序，
which we're going to think about in the setting
我们将在环境中考虑
of a problem called job scheduling.
问题称为作业调度。
So job scheduling, we are given a directed acyclic graph.
因此，在作业调度中，我们得到了有向无环图。
I want to order the vertices so that all edges point
我想对顶点进行排序，以便所有边都指向
from lower order to high order.
从低阶到高阶。
Directed acyclic graph is called a DAG,
有向无环图称为DAG，
you should know that from 042.
您应该从042知道这一点。
And maybe I'll draw one for kicks.
也许我会抽一踢。
Now, I've drawn the graph so all the edges go left to right,
现在，我已经绘制了图形，因此所有边缘从左到右，
so you can see that there's no cycles here,
这样您就可以看到这里没有周期，
but generally you'd run DFS and you'd detect there's no cycles.
但通常您会运行DFS，并且会发现没有周期。
And now, imagine these vertices represent
现在，假设这些顶点代表
things you need to do.
您需要做的事情。
The textbook has a funny example where you're getting dressed,
教科书上有一个有趣的例子，说明您穿衣服的样子，
so you have these constraints that say,
所以你有这些约束说
well, I've got to put my socks on before put my shoes on.
好吧，我得先穿袜子，然后再穿鞋。
And then I've got to put my underwear on before I
然后我必须先穿上内衣
put my pants on, and all these kinds of things.
穿上我的裤子，以及所有类似的东西。
You would code that as a directed acyclic graph.
您可以将其编码为有向无环图。
You hope there's no cycles, because then you
您希望没有周期，因为那样您
can't get dressed.
不能穿衣服。
And there's some things, like, well, I
还有一些事情，例如，我
could put my glasses on whenever, although actually I
可以随时戴上眼镜，尽管实际上我
should put my glasses on before I do anything else,
在我做其他事情之前，应该戴上眼镜，
otherwise there's problems.
否则会有问题。
I don't know, you could put your watch on at any time,
我不知道，您可以随时戴上手表，
unless you need to know what time is.
除非您需要知道现在几点。
So there's some disconnected parts, whatever.
因此，有一些断开的部分，无论如何。
There's some unrelated things, like, I
有一些无关的东西，例如我
don't care the order between my shirt and my pants
不在乎我的衬衫和裤子之间的顺序
or whatever, some things aren't constrained.
或其他任何东西都不受限制。
What you'd like to do is choose an actual order to do things.
您要做的是选择实际的订单来做事。
Say you're a sequential being, you
说你是一个有序的人，你
can only do one thing at a time, so I
一次只能做一件事，所以我
want to compute a total order.
想要计算总订单。
First I'll do g, then I'll do a, then
首先我会做g，然后我会做a，然后
I can do h, because I've done both of the predecessors.
我可以做h，因为我已经做过两个前任。
Then I can't do be, because I haven't done d,
那我就做不到，因为我还没做过d，
so maybe I'll do d first, and then b, and than e, then c,
所以也许我先做d，然后做b，然后再做e，然后做c，
then f, then i.
然后是f，然后是i。
That would be a valid order, because all edges point
那将是一个有效的顺序，因为所有边缘都指向
from an earlier number to a later number.
从较早的数字到较新的数字。
So that's the goal.
这就是目标。
And these are real job scheduling problems
这些都是真正的工作安排问题
that come up, you'll see more applications
出现，您将看到更多应用程序
in your problem set.
在您的问题集中。
How do we do this?
我们如何做到这一点？
Well, at this point we have two algorithms,
好了，目前我们有两种算法
and I pretty much revealed it is DFS.
我几乎透露它是DFS。
DFS will do this.
DFS将执行此操作。
It's a topological sort, is what this algorithm is usually
这是一种拓扑排序，通常是这种算法
called.
叫。
Topological sort because you're given a graph, which
拓扑排序，因为您得到了一个图，
you could think of as a topology.
您可以将其视为拓扑。
You want to sort it, in a certain sense.
从某种意义上说，您想对其进行排序。
It's not like sorting numbers, it's
这不像对数字进行排序，而是
sorting vertices in a graph, so, hence, topological sort.
在图中对顶点进行排序，因此是拓扑排序。
That's the name of the algorithm.
那就是算法的名字。
And it's run DFS, and output the reverse
然后运行DFS，并输出相反的结果
of the finishing times of vertices.
顶点的整理时间。
so this is another application where you really
所以这是您真正在其中的另一个应用程序
want to visit all the vertices in the graph,
想要访问图中的所有顶点，
so we use this top level DFS, so everybody gets visited.
因此我们使用此顶级DFS，因此每个人都可以访问。
And there are these finishing times,
还有这些完成时间，
so every time I finish a vertex, I could add it to a list.
因此，每次完成顶点时，都可以将其添加到列表中。
Say OK, that one was finished next,
说好，那下一个完成了，
than this one is finished, than this one's finished.
比这完成的还要多。
I take that order and I reverse it.
我接受该命令，然后我将其撤消。
That will be a topological order.
那将是一个拓扑顺序。
Why?
为什么？
Who knows.
谁知道。
Let's prove it.
让我们证明一下。
We've actually done pretty much the hard work, which
实际上，我们已经做了很多艰苦的工作，
is to say-- we're assuming our graph has no cycles,
就是说-我们假设我们的图表没有周期，
so that tells us by this cycle detection
这样通过周期检测可以告诉我们
that there are no back edges.
没有后边缘。
Back edges are kind of the annoying part.
后边缘有点烦人。
Now they don't exist here.
现在它们在这里不存在。
So all the edges are tree edges, forward edges, and cross edges,
所以所有的边都是树边，前边和交叉边，
and we use that to prove the theorem.
我们用它来证明定理。
So we want to prove that all the edges point from an earlier
因此，我们想证明所有边缘都指向较早的
number to a later number.
编号到更高的编号。
So what that means is for an edge,
所以这意味着优势
uv, we want to show that v finishes before u.
uv，我们想证明v在u之前完成。
That's the reverse, because what we're taking
恰恰相反，因为我们要采取的是
is the reverse of the finishing order.
是完成顺序的相反顺序。
So edge uv, I want to make sure v finishes first,
因此，在uv边缘，我想确保v首先完成，
so that u will be ordered first.
这样您将被首先订购。
Well, there are two cases.
好吧，有两种情况。
Case 1 is that u starts before v. Case 2
情况1是u在v之前开始
is that he v before u.
是他在你之前v。
At some point they start, because we
他们从某个时候开始，因为我们
visit the whole graph.
访问整个图表。
This top loop guarantees that.
这个顶级循环保证了这一点。
So consider what order we visit them first, at the beginning,
因此，首先考虑一下我们首先拜访他们的顺序，
and then we'll think about how they finish.
然后我们将考虑它们如何完成。
Well, this case is kind of something we've seen before.
好吧，这种情况是我们以前见过的。
We visit u, we have not yet visited v,
我们访问过您，我们尚未访问过v，
but v is reachable from u, so maybe via this edge,
但是v可以从u到达，所以也许可以通过这个边，
or maybe via some other path, we will eventually
或者也许通过其他途径，我们最终
visit v in the recursion for u.
在您的递归中访问v。
So before u finishes, we will visit v, visit v
因此，在您完成操作之前，我们将访问v，访问v
before u finishes.
在你完成之前。
That sentence is just like this sentence,
那句话就像这句话
so same kind of argument.
这样的论点。
We won't go into detail, because we already
我们不会详细介绍，因为我们已经
did that several times.
做了几次。
So that means we'll visit v, we will completely visit v,
因此，这意味着我们将访问v，我们将完全访问v，
we will finish v before we finish u
我们将在完成u之前完成v
and that's what we wanted to prove.
这就是我们想要证明的。
So in that case is good.
所以在那种情况下是好的。
The other cases is that v starts before u.
其他情况是v在u之前开始。
Here, you might get slightly worried.
在这里，您可能会有些担心。
So we have an edge, uv, still, same direction.
所以我们有一个边缘，uv，仍然是同一方向。
But now we start at v, u has not yet been visited.
但是现在我们从v开始，尚未访问过u。
Well, now we worry that we visit u.
好吧，现在我们担心我们会拜访您。
If we visit u, we're going to finish u before we finish v,
如果我们访问您，我们将在完成v之前完成u，
but we want it to be the other way around.
但我们希望反之亦然。
Why can't that happen?
为什么那不可能发生？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Because there's a back edge somewhere here.
教授：因为这里有后缘。
In particular, the graph would have to be cyclic.
特别地，该图将必须是循环的。
This is a cycle, so this can't happen, a contradiction.
这是一个周期，所以这不可能发生，是一个矛盾。
So v will finish before we visit u at all.
因此v将在我们完全访问您之前完成。
So v will still finish first, because we don't even touch u,
v仍然会先完成，因为我们甚至都不会碰你，
because there's no cycles.
因为没有周期。
So that's actually the proof that topological sort gives you
所以这实际上是拓扑排序给您的证明
a valid job schedule, and it's kind of-- there
有效的工作时间表，在某种程度上
are even more things you can do with DFS.
您可以使用DFS做更多的事情。
We'll see some in recitations, more in the textbook.
我们将在背诵中看到一些内容，在教科书中还会更多。
But simple algorithm, can do a lot of nifty things with it,
但是简单的算法可以用它做很多漂亮的事情，
very fast, linear time.
非常快的线性时间。